blaupunkt.com 2019-02-25

# BLAUPUNKT: Privacy Statement

## Privacy Statement 

The GIP Development appreciates your interest in its products and your visit to this website.

**The GIP Development respects your Privacy**  
The protection of your privacy in the processing of your personal data is an important concern to which we pay special attention during our business processes. Personal data collected during visits to our websites are processed by us confidentially and according to the legal provisions. Data protection and Information security are part of our company policy. Blaupunkt websites may include links to other websites which are not covered by this privacy statement.

**Collection and Processing of Personal Data**  
When you visit our websites our web server automatically records the name of your internet service provider, the website from which you visit us, the websites you actually visit and the date and length of your visit. Blaupunkt may use cookies and active components (e.g. JavaScript) to follow the preferences of our visitors and optimize our websites accordingly. You can reset your browser either to notify you when you receive a cookie, or to refuse to accept cookies. Please note that certain areas of most sites may not function properly if you reject a cookie.  
Additional personal data is only stored if volunteered by you, for example in context of a registration, a survey, a contest or in execution of a contract.

**googleAnalytics**  
This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States . Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

**Use and Disclosure of Personal Data and Purpose Specification**  
The GIP Development will use your personal data for the sole purpose of technical administration of the websites, customer administration, product surveys and marketing, only to the extent necessary in each specific case. Your personal data will not be disclosed to third parties outside the GIP Development without your consent.

**Security**  
The GIP Development uses security measures in order to protect the data we have under our control against manipulation, loss, destruction, access by unauthorized persons or against unauthorized disclosure. Our security procedures are continually enhanced as new technology becomes available.

**Freedom of choice**  
We would like to use your data to inform you about our products and services and request your opinion, where applicable. Naturally your participation in such campaigns is voluntary. Should you not consent, you can inform us at any time, so that we can prohibit the use of your data accordingly. For further information we refer you to the local website-services.
